What is Linux.
So of course we are going to learn Linux but we do want to know what exactly is.
Linux is an operating system.
It's just like any other operating system.
For example Microsoft has Windows.
Apple has Mac sun which is now owned by Oracle.
They have Solaris running on sparc hardware.
So Linux is an operating system which sits in the middle of your hardware and the users and the users
are the ones who run the applications.
So it's like a middleman or a bridge that takes the commands from users and translate them to hardware.
So look at this picture.
So you see a computer right.
So without an operating system this computer is considered like a dumb terminal.
It doesn't do anything.
So how does it work.
So we have this terminal which is of course a piece of brick.
You open the tray of their computer you insert your CD or DVD in that CD or DVD has the operating system
image sitting on it whether it's a Windows or Linux or whichever operating system that you are installing.
So you boot your computer from that operating system.
So once you're booting it up it goes through the installation process that installation process is going
to ask you a bunch of questions like How do you want the operating system to configure how you want
your dissertation.
How do you want.
How many users you want to have installed and so on.
So once the installation is done then at the end of the installation it's going to ask you to reboot
reboot the computer and it comes up to the Volcom screen and say welcome to Linux or Welcome to Windows
or watch every operating system that you are installing.
So then you could attach external devices to it.
For example you could attach a keyboard to it.
You could attach mouse to it.
So you use these mouse in keyboards you type a certain command certain you use applications and type
them and then you send it to your operating system.
Then you operate system takes those commands and forward it to other hardware or other system of peripherals.
So some of them are for example the printer.
So you if you are running an application for example you're running microsoft word you type it in with
your keyboard and then you want to print that document right.
So the operating system will take that document and send it to your printer and your printer will spit
out the document that you wanted to print.
Or if you're running other programs for example you are online you're checking your e-mail or you are
running some online program where you win games.
So you are using your keyboard or your mouse you communicating with your operating system and the heart
operating system can communicate with your hardware and that's how we make haste to other devices on
the network.